onpage.org 2019-03-31

# Ryte: Privacy - usage of cookies, personal data and more

Please note: The [German Privacy Policy](https://de.ryte.com/about/privacy/) is binding.

Data Protection Declaration

We are pleased that you are visiting our website and show an interest in our company. We take the protection of your personal data seriously and want to ensure that you feel secure and enjoy visiting our internet pages.

 **1\. General**  
You agree to the German Privacy Policy which has been translated to English for your convenience only. The German Privacy Policy is binding.  
Ryte GmbH places the highest significance on the protection of the privacy of its users. This applies particularly to the processing of personal data. You don’t have to reveal personal data when using our website. In certain cases we do, however, need your name and address as well as further data in order to process your order. Where this is needed we will point this out to you as appropriate. In addition, we will only store and process data which you have voluntarily or automatically provided us with. 

**2\. Acquisition and Processing**  
Every access to our website and all calling up of underlying data are recorded. These include: the data names of called-up data and the date and time of the call, the volume of data transmitted, notification of successful call-ups and the web browser and domain of the enquirer. This recording is for internal statistical reasons. The IP addresses of the computers from which the requests were issued are also recorded. Going forward, personal data will only be stored if you have given it freely in connection with a question, an order or registration.

 **3\. Usage and Transmission**  
We will handle the personal data you revealed confidentially and only reveal it to third parties if required by order processing, for example by passing order data to deliverers. In no case would we sell or rent your personal data or data that could be linked to you to third parties for them to use. Personal data will only be used to process your orders, to answer your questions and for internal compilation of anonymized statistics. The only exceptions will consist of services ordered by you which will include your consent to the further use of data you provided and by the relaying of data to public institutions and authorities as required by law. We will, with your agreement, pass your compiled and stored data to our business partners under the aegis of contractual agreements, insofar as it is necessary in your interests. Of course, our business partners are called upon and obliged to comply with legal data protection regulations.  
We will identify any advertising for other organizations on our Internet site insofar as we advertise them. According to the court decision of 12th May 1998, “Liability for Links” (312 O 85/98), the Hamburg district court clearly decided that an organization, by installing a link, becomes jointly responsible for, which means liable for, the contents of the linked site; this can only be prevented if the linking organization clearly distances itself from these contents which Ryte GmbH hereby does.  
Ryte GmbH will not transmit data to non-EU states without your agreement except where it is necessary for transaction processing and is explicitly allowed by the BDSG.

 **4\. Your Rights and Choices**  
You can access, rectify, erase, restrict or export your personal information at any time by emailing us at info@ryte.com or by post:  
Ryte GmbH  
Geschäftsleitung  
Paul-Heyse-Straße 27  
80336 München

You can object to our processing of your personal information at any time. Contact our Data Protection Officer with requests or concerns

Mr Stefan Eisert  
SEDC  
Magdalenenweg 12  
85457 Wörth  
Tel.: 08123 928639  
Mobile: 0173 481 6006  
sedc1@web.de

Of course, if you are affected, you can also turn to the regional office for data protection control:

BayLDA  
Promenade 27  
91522 Ansbach  
Tel: 0981 531300  
poststelle@lda.bayern.de

You have the right to have data we have collected either with your permission or automatically while fulfilling a contract, in an established, machine-readable format, sent to you or third party. If you have asked for the transmission of data to another responsible party, this will only be done to the extent it is technically feasible.

Stored personal data will be deleted if the website user and/or customer cancels their permission for it to be stored or if their knowledge is no longer necessary for the fulfilment of whatever purpose caused them to be stored or if their storage becomes impermissible for other legal reasons. Data needed for calculation of invoices or for book-keeping reasons are unaffected by this.

 **5\. Usage of Cookies**  
In order to make your visit to our website more appealing and to enable the use of certain features, we employ so-called cookies on several sites. In so doing, small text files are deposited on your terminal device. Some of the cookies employed by us will be deleted after finishing your browser session, hence closing your browser (so-called Session Cookies). Other cookies will remain on your device and enable us or our business partners to recognize your browser on your next visit (Persistent Cookies). You can adjust your browser in order to notify you about the setting of new cookies and decide whether to accept cookies for certain cases or to generally decline them. With declining cookies, our website’s functionality can be limited.

 **6\. Usage of third party tools**  
In the following section you can find all third party tools Ryte uses.  
a) Google  
Unless otherwise stated in this privacy policy, the operator of all Google services mentioned here is Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”).

 **i) Google Tag Manager**  
This website uses the “Google Tag Manager” service. The Tag Manager is a tool for the management of so-called tags, which are used for tracking in online marketing. The Tag Manager itself does not process any personal data, since it is purely for the administration of other services - e.g. Google Analytics, etc. -.  
For more information about the Tag Manager, please visit the [privacy policy](https://www.google.com/analytics/tag-manager/use-policy/).

 **ii) Google Analytics**  
Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics tool of the Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies”, text files which are being stored on your computer and enable the analysis of your usage of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your usage of the website is generally transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. In case of activated IP anonymization on this website, Google will however shorten your IP address within EU member states or other contracting states of the European Economic Area Agreement.  
Only on rare occasions, the entire IP address will be transferred to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. On behalf of the website operator, Google will use this information to analyze your usage of the website in order to compose reports about the website activities and to perform further services related to the website and web usage towards the website operator. The transfer of your IP address for the purposes of Google Analytics won’t be merged with other Google data.  
You can prevent your browser software from storing cookies with a respective change of settings; we however point to the fact that in this case you may not be able to use all features of this website to its full extent. Moreover, you can prevent the assessment of the data generated by the cookie and related to your usage of the website (including your IP address) as well as Google processing this data with downloading and installing the following browser Plug-In retrievable from <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

**iii) Google+ Plug-Ins (e.g. “+1” button)**  
Our website uses so-called Social Plug-Ins (“Plug-Ins”) of the social network Google+. The Plug-Ins are e.g. recognizable from buttons with “+1” on blank or colored background. Please find an overview of the Google Plug-Ins and their appearance here: https://developers.google.com/+/plugins.  
If you click on sites of our website containing such Plug-Ins, your browser automatically establishes a connection with the Google servers. Google will transfer the content of the Plug-In directly to your browser and integrate it into the site. With that integration, Google receives the information that your browser has called the respective site of our website, even if you don’t have a Google+ profile or are not logged into Google+. This information (including your IP address) will be sent from your browser directly to a Google server in the USA and stored there.  
If you are logged into Google+, Google can directly correlate your visit of our website with your Google+ profile. If you interact with the Plug-Ins, for instance clicking the “+1” button, the respective information will also be directly sent to a Google server and stored there. Moreover, the information will be published on Google+ and available for your contacts.  
For sense and purpose of the data assessment and further processing and use of your data through Google as well as rights concerning this matter and the setup of the protection of your privacy, please refer to the Google privacy policy: https://developers.google.com/+/web/buttons-policy  
If you don’t want Google to instantly correlate the information gathered on our website with your Google+ profile, you need to log out from Google+ before visiting our website. You can also completely prevent loading Google Plug-Ins with Add-Ons for your browser, e.g. with “NoScript” (<https://noscript.net/>).

 **iv) Google AdWords**  
Ryte uses the “Google AdWords” service. This service has the purpose of so-called 'conversion tracking', i.e. we can see what happened after you have clicked on one of our ads. Cookies are used for this purpose, which have a limited validity and do not contain any personal data. Personal identification of the user is therefore not possible.

Our legitimate interest in using this service is to analyze and optimize the operation of our website.

 **v) Doubleclick by Google**  
This website uses the “Doubleclick by Google” service. This service uses cookies to show you advertisements relevant to you. This is done by means of a pseudonymous identification number (pID) which your browser receives and is assigned to it. With this pID the service can recognize which displays have already been displayed and which have been called. The cookies used do not contain any personal data. Rather, the cookies serve a cross website placement of advertisements by enabling Google to identify the pages visited. The information generated by the cookies is transmitted by Google to a server in the USA for analysis and stored there. A transfer of data by Google to third parties only takes place due to legal regulations or within the scope of order data processing. Under no circumstances will Google match your data with other data collected by Google.

By using our website, you consent to your data being processed by Google in accordance with the description and purposes set out above. You can prevent the use of cookies by making the appropriate settings in your browser. However, such an attitude can lead to the fact that the website cannot be used without restrictions.  
Google is [Privacy Shield certified](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active).

 **b) Twitter**  
Our website uses so-called Social Plug-Ins (“Plug-Ins”) of the micro blogging platform Twitter, which is being operated from the Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“twitter”). The Plug-Ins are marked with a Twitter logo, e.g. in form of the blue “Twitter bird”. Please find an overview of the Twitter Plug-Ins and their appearance [here](https://twitter.com/about/resources/buttons).  
If you click on sites of our website containing such Plug-Ins, your browser automatically establishes a connection with the Twitter servers. Twitter will transfer the content of the Plug-In directly to your browser and integrate it into the site. With that integration, Twitter receives the information that your browser has called the respective site of our website, even if you don’t have a Twitter profile or are not logged into Twitter. This information (including your IP address) will be sent from your browser directly to a Twitter server in the USA and stored there.  
If you are logged into Twitter, Twitter can directly correlate your visit of our website with your Twitter profile. If you interact with the Plug-Ins, for instance clicking the “Tweet” button, the respective information will also be directly sent to a Twitter server and stored there. Moreover, the information will be published in your Twitter account and available for your contacts.  
For sense and purpose of the data assessment and further processing and use of your data through Twitter as well as rights concerning this matter and the setup of the protection of your privacy, please refer to the Twitter [privacy policy](https://twitter.com/privacy).

If you don’t want Twitter to instantly correlate the information gathered on our website with your Twitter profile, you need to log out from Twitter before visiting our website. You can also completely prevent loading Twitter Plug-Ins with Add-Ons for your browser, e.g. with “NoScript”.

 **c) Facebook**   
Unless otherwise stated in this privacy policy, the operator of all Facebook services mentioned here is Facebook Inc., 1601 p. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”).

 **i) Custom Audiences**  
This website uses the 'Facebook Custom Audiences' service. This service enables us to address the user with interest-based advertising on the social network - Facebook.

To make this possible, we have implemented the Facebook Remarketing Tag on our website. This tag establishes a direct connection to Facebook servers when you visit the website. This gives Facebook information about the pages you have visited on our site. Facebook then compares it with your Facebook account. The next time you visit Facebook, you will be shown personalized, interest-based ads - Facebook ads.

Our legitimate interest in the use of this service lies in targeting the users of the website with advertising.

For more information, please see Facebook's [privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).  
Facebook is [Privacy Shield certified](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active).

 **ii) Facebook Connect**  
We also use Facebook Connect to allow you to sign up and log in using your Facebook account. If you sign up using Facebook Connect, Facebook will ask your permission to share certain information from your Facebook account with us. This may include your first name, last name, email address in order for us to verify your identity and gender, general location, a link to your Facebook profile, your timezone, birthday, profile picture, your 'likes' and your list of friends. This information is collected by Facebook and is provided to us under the terms of Facebook’s privacy policy which you can find [here](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php).

You can control the information that we receive from Facebook using the privacy settings in your Facebook account.

 **d) Zendesk**  
In our software we use the Customer Support Management service of Zendesk Inc., 989 Market Street #300, San Francisco, CA 94102, USA (“Zendesk”).

Our legitimate interest in using this service is to be able to answer user requests quickly and efficiently. Zendesk uses your data only to forward your enquiries to us. The data will not be passed on to third parties.

To use Zendesk, you must enter at least one correct email address. The service can also be used pseudonymised. During the processing of service requests, it may be necessary to collect further data (e.g. first name, surname, address, etc.). The use of Zendesk is optional. If you do not agree to Zendesk collecting your information, we offer you alternative ways to contact us by phone or mail to submit service requests.

For more information, please see Zendesk's [privacy policy](https://www.zendesk.de/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/).  
Zendesk is [Privacy Shield certified](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TOjeAAG&status=Active).

 **e) Intercom**  
In our software we use the Customer Messaging Platform Intercom Inc., 55 2nd Street, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA (“Intercom”).

Our legitimate interest in using this service is to be able to answer customer requests quickly and efficiently. Intercom uses your data only to forward your enquiries to us. The data will not be passed on to third parties.

To use Intercom, you must be a customer of our software. During the processing of service requests, it may be necessary to collect further data (e.g. first name, surname, address, etc.).

For more information, please see Intercom's [privacy policy](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy).  
Intercom is [Privacy Shield certified](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TNQvAAO&status=Active).

 **f) Hotjar**  
This website uses the All-in-one Analytics and Feedback software Hotjar Ltd., St Julian’s Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julian’s STJ 1000, Malta (“Hotjar”).

We use Hotjar to create heat maps and anonymized visitor recordings. The implemented tracking code and related cookie about your use of the webpage will be submitted and stored by Hotjar in Ireland.  
In order to disable Hotjar, you can [opt-out of Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out) on your browser.

For more information, please see Hotjar's privacy policy.  
Privacy Shield certified: Since Hotjar is a company registered in the European Union, it does not need to comply with this framework.

 **g) Wistia**  
This website uses the Video Software Wistia Ltd., 17 Tudor Street, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 02139, USA (“Wistia”).

We use Wistia to track user behavior while viewing videos on the Ryte website, including the portion of video(s) watched, buttons clicked on the video and video completion rates. Wistia doesn’t save any personal data.

For more information, please see Wistia's [privacy policy](https://wistia.com/privacy).  
Wistia is [Privacy Shield certified](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TSBFAA4&status=Active).

 **h) Act-On Software**  
On this website we use Act-On Inc., 121 SW Morrison St., Suite 1600, Portland, OR 97204, USA (“Act-On”) for our online marketing activities.

This is an integrated software solution with which we cover various aspects of our online marketing. These include, among other things: E-mail marketing (newsletters as well as automated mailings), contact management (e.g. user segmentation & CRM) and forms.

Our website allows visitors to register and download content by giving us their contact information. This information can be used by us to contact website visitors and to determine which services of our company are of interest to them. 

Our legitimate interest in the use of this service is the optimization of our marketing measures.

For more information, please see Act-On’s [privacy policy](https://www.act-on.com/privacy-policy/).   
Act-On is [Privacy Shield certified](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000KzMNAA0&status=Active).

 **i) Track JS LLC**  
In our software we use TrackJS Service (The “Service”) operated by TrackJS, LLC (or “TrackJS”),

Track JS is a an error tracking service for web application. While tracking errors in our software we store the browser, IP address and operating system on which the error occured.  
Our legitimate interest to use TrackJS is to prevent errors displayed to our users in the software.

For more information, please see TrackJS’s [privacy policy](https://trackjs.com/privacy/).

 **j) Pingdom**  
This website uses Pingdom, a web analysis service from Solarwinds, 7171 Southwest Parkway Bldg 400, Austin, Texas, 78735, USA (“Pingdom”).   
Pingdom uses so-called 'cookies', which are text files that are stored on your computer and enable analysis of the website use. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Pingdom server in the USA and stored there.  
You may prevent the storing of cookies by using the appropriate setting in your browser's software.  
Our legitimate right to use Pingdom is to analyse and regularly improve the use of our website. By using the statistics, we can improve our website and make it more interesting for you, as the user.  
For more information, please see Pingdom’s [privacy policy](https://www.solarwinds.com/legal/privacy).

 **k)** OneSignal  
In the Ryte magazin and product insights blog we use OneSignal, a message sending service, 2194 Esperanca Avenue, Santa Clara, CA 95054, USA (“OneSignal”).

Our legitimate interest to use OneSignal is to send push-notifications about new articles to users on the web. You can decide on your own in our Ryte magazine and product insights if you want to subscribe to push notifications.  
You can opt-out push notifications by going to your device “Settings” and clicking on “Notifications,” and then changing those settings for some or all of the apps on your device.

For more information, please see OneSignal’s [privacy policy](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy).

 **l) Disqus**  
Disqus is an online service provider of Disqus, Inc, 301 Howard St, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA, (“Disqus“), which provides a centralized discussion platform for websites.

In our Ryte magazine and product insights blog, we have integrated Disqus plugins that allow website visitors to post comments on our websites and link comments across multiple sites (including third party websites).  
If you enter a page on our website which includes a Disqus plug-in, your browser will establish a direct connection to the Disqus servers from where the plug-in is loaded. The information that your browser visited the corresponding page of our online services is transmitted to Disqus, even if you do not have a Disqus account or are not logged into your account. This information is sent directly from your browser to a Disqus server in the USA and stored there. If you log into your Disqus account at the same time, it is also possible to assign the page retrieval to your Disqus account and allow Disqus to assign your surfing behavior directly to your account. If you want to block the transmission and storage of your data and your behaviour, you must log out of your Disqus account before you visit our website and delete any cookies placed by Disqus.  
To post a comment on our website (using a Disqus plug-in), you must log into your Disqus account. When you post a comment on the website, Disqus collects information about your visit to our website and other websites, including the information you post and your IP address. Your comment will be sent directly to the Disqus servers through an iframe.  
For more information, please see Disqus [privacy policy](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy).  
Disqus is [Privacy Shield certified](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TRkEAAW&status=Active).

 **m) Mixpanel**  
Our website and software use the analytics platform Mixpanel Inc., 405 Howard St., Floor 2, San Francisco, California 94105, USA („Mixpanel”).This services enables companies to get automatic insights into user behavior in order to improve the customer experience.Ryte gives your first name, last name and email address to Mixpanel after you have successfully logged in to our software.To disable Mixpanel, you can opt-out of Mixpanel on your browser: <https://help.mixpanel.com/hc/en-us/articles/360000679006-Managing-Personal-Information#optout-users> Our legitimate interest in the use of this service is to analyze, optimize and monitor the user experience of our software users.For more information, please see Mixpanel’s privacy policy: https:<https://mixpanel.com/legal/privacy-overview/> Mixpanel is Privacy Shield certified: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TOacAAGbv>

**8 ) SSL-Encryption**  
For security and for protection during the transmission of confidential contents such as, for example, inquiries, this page uses SSL-encryption. You can detect an encrypted connection from the lock symbol in the browser row and that the URL address changes from 'http://' to 'https://'. If SSL-encryption is activated the data you transmit cannot be read by third parties

 **9) Newsletter**  
It is up to you if you want to register for our newsletter. In all our registration forms you can find a checkbox for our newsletter. Once you registered we need your email address confirmation that you are the owner of the stated email address and that you agree to the receipt of newsletters (double opt-in). These data are only generated for the purpose of sending you the newsletter and to enable us to document our related authority to do so. We use a service provider to send out the newsletters and they store your data according to the legal guidelines. Your order of the newsletters and your permission to store your email address can be cancelled at any time. 

**10) Security notice**  
We assure you that we store your personal data with the help of all technical and organizational possibilities so that they are not accessible to third parties. When communicating by e-mail, we cannot guarantee complete data security, so we recommend that you send confidential information by post.

Stand: 10.08.2018
